

07030648749 michaelakindolie@gmail.com 12 olowu street, Ipaja, Lagos 100001 Nigeria

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

An innovation and technology enthusiast with over 4 years of experience in application development. Problem solver and experienced in phases of an agile-friendly software development life-cycle. A full-stack developer with industry experience in both backend and frontend development.

### **SKILLS**

- HTML5/CSS3
- Flutter
- C
- Oracle SQL
- Oracle APEX
- Adobe XD
- Oracle SQL Developer
- Postman
- Problem-solving
- Technology integration
- Networking

- JavaScript
- Dart
- PLSQL
- GIT
- Figma
- Jaspersoft Studio
- Oracle Data Modeler
- Teamwork
- Creative thinking
- Best practices implementation

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Software Developer, Neulogic Solutions Limited**, Apr 2018 - Current, Ilupeju, , Lagos Nigeria

- Integrated design feedback to build and maintain user-centered software applications.
- Coded programs in diverse programming languages based on specific functionality requirements.
- Integrated advanced technologies and tools to improve software performance.
- Employed best practices in software development to complete high-quality applications in line with schedule targets.
- Contributed to code reviews, debugging, and optimization for Symplus and Customer Portal software.
- Maintained and updated files and records to support efficient deployment operations.
- Maintained good working relationships with co-workers and management.
- Maintained detailed documentation of software development processes and updates.

Mathematics Teacher, Luminary Schools Edjeba (NYSC), Jan 2017 - Nov 2017, Warri, Delta Nigeria

- Demonstrated mathematical concepts in relatable ways and with numerous real-world examples.
- Customized teaching approaches based on understanding and abilities of different student groups.
- Helped chose, revise, and approve mathematics curricula and lessons.
- Held regular office hours to help struggling students understand concepts and improve abilities.

Undergraduate Intern, Tech Accelerate Africa, Nov 2015 - Jan 2016, Ikeja, Lagos Nigeria

- Configuration and Software Installation on new systems
- Web development using Wix
- Hour of Code Project: Awareness and facilitation
- Online Survey Project for Tertiary Institution: Survey design and distribution
- Worked on special projects, taking the lead on important project initiatives.
- Prioritized and managed multiple tasks and competing priorities in servicing requests from senior managers.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Nov 2016

# Federal University, Oye Ekiti. - Oye Ekiti, Ekiti, Nigeria

- Graduated with honors (Second Class Upper)
- GPA 4.2.
- Member, NACOSS (National Association of Computer Science Students).